So the next thing we're going to do is talk about something that is common in a lot of apps
particularly view and so we're going to talk about event handlers and so when we talk about event handlers as a brief recap
if we take a look at let's go actually let's go to our new restaurant form this is probably the best place to take a look at this
is that we have this thing down here when we're creating
and you'll notice that we're inlining this admit right
and it says oh admit new restaurant, ad new restaurant, past new restaurant
but again one of the problems with this is that it's buried inside of our code
and so let's go first up by refactoring this so we can talk more about what we're going to do with this
so personally I tried to avoid inlining the dollar sign admit inside of the template whenever possible
just because it's really oftentimes it's a bit of logic that you want to be able to call
multiple times
so what I would typically do then is let's go ahead and swap this over to setup
we're going to delete these two
then we'll define our emits
such
and then let's just comment that out real quick
we'll cast it
so the first one is an event called ad new restaurant
where we take a type of restaurant which should be a type restaurant
then basically we have the same thing for the second one
but this one it's cancel new restaurant and actually it doesn't have a payload at all
and then we just need to define what's being returned nothing
so we just add void and there we go
now we have that and then before we finish up let's do this
cons new restaurant is a ref that is from view
wrap all that
and then what's nice now is that because restaurant side of the list is being imported
I don't need to declare it a second time
so this is how this ends up shaking out once we've migrated it
okay
so let me go ahead and start by just committing this to the
exercise branch so you can see the progression
the factor
move
new restaurant
great
so what we'll notice here now
is we have this emit here happening
but I actually just probably want to just call
an ad restaurant function
I think inlining it this way is the cleanest way
to just be like okay there's going to be a function that's run on click
no one has to worry about lightweight what's all the sign what's a bit
no there's an ad function called ad restaurant
okay then how are we going to define that well let's go ahead and do that
so actually I'm going to add this below so
constant ad restaurant
is the function
and that function
when clicked upon will
emits what will it emit
well we can actually we don't have our emits defined so we just need to declare it here
and then we can say emit what
let's see emit click control space
ah and you restaurant yes that's what I want
I got a love autocomplete because I just reduced the number of
typos I have and then new restaurant dot value
I think that should do it
except oh interesting look it's yelling at us why
because it's saying wait what is this
object you're passing me it's not really a restaurant well we can fix that
we just pass it here and define it there
and voila
now you have everything very consistently typed as we've been learning so far
and so now if we go ahead and go inside of our app
go the other way
so instead of new
and then we'll be like
uh been yay and the juts
test dot com
create
for somebody the title disappeared but we'll figure that out in a second oh I think I know why
uh I think I think I do know why
okay so clearly something is being added to the
because okay so actually let me explain this part
because I forgot when we emit the restaurant what's happening is that
the parent component that
it lives on which is currently parent page
you'll notice that when we scroll down
restaurant uh the new restaurant form here
this is where we're actually calling like basically we're listening for the event
so I just multi-line this just make this a little bit easier to read
but it's basically when you declare a custom event in view like
adne restaurant it's basically saying we can listen to this thing called adne
restaurant when this event is triggered
run this function
basically within the parent component
so this ad restaurant here is being triggered
right here
and so this is where again now our work that we were doing before
starts to come together because why we know that the payload is supposed to be restaurant
and that's what's being passed defined at the emit
so we have consistency here
and then we know that okay restaurant lives value push
great high form this is starting to come together really nicely
okay so that looks good
but we have this uh we have a slight problem so let me
first start by let's refactor this one real quick to cancel
restaurant new restaurant
and then now that we have that
we'll just copy this real quick
and notice a cancel new restaurant
emit what commands control space
wait that's the wrong one
trying to be smart because you have the second argument
oh I think you're actually right
because so um was mentioned in the class here is that
currently it knows that cancel new restaurant does not have a parameter
but adne restaurant does so we strip this out
we should see there it is
it's being a little bit too smart
but that was very nice
so now we have this now everything's refactor
correctly we're good
I do see a red squiggle line but we'll deal with that in a second
okay so let's finish up that refactor